DHR&Hakugetsu Sub
翻譯：因果律 モビイ·ディック 大湿 時間軸：KoU 後期：水姬 壓制：沙夏 KoU
For crying out loud, Chihiro...
Why are you asking me to do this?
ま～ったく　千紘のヤツ
何で私に頼むかな～
早く来いよ
Come on, hurry up!
Wait up!
待ってよ
Geez, I'm gonna leave you behind!
もう　置いていくぞ
No, don't!
ヤダよ
うわ～ん！
Nemurenai yoru ni kiita monogatari ga
What if the story I heard that sleepless night
esoragoto da to shitara
was all just an impossible dream?
Eien wo shiru yori kairaku wo motomete
What if I pursue pleasure, and lament the moment
ima wo kuyande shimau no wa
instead of learning about the eternities
kokoro no fukaku ni sumitsuita kage kara
so that I can escape from the shadows
nigeru tame da to shitara
that dwell deep within my heart?
Sore demo atashi wa atashi wa ai shite irareru nara
But even so, as long as I, as long as I can still keep loving
Hanbun ni wareta taiyou ga asa wo tsurete kite
The sun split in half brings with it the morning
yami ni nareta shinkei wo jiwari shigeki suru
gradually stimulating my nerves, so used to the darkness
Okiwasureta ano ai wa aete sono mama de
I'll dare to leave the love that I'd misplaced as it is
Shinario no kieta monogatari wa
A story whose plot has been erased,
jiyuu ni jiyuu ni kaji wo totte
freely, freely, takes the helm,
motto takaku e maiagatte
soaring ever higher
はい
Here.
Wow, this looks delicious.
うわッ　おいしそうだ
キレイだね
It's so pretty.
You're right. It's surprising.
ホント　いい香り
"Childhood... Friends..."
- Thank you for this meal.
- I'm Saoji Ranko, second-year,
Sanka Private Academy.
- Thank you for this meal.
私は左王子蘭子
私立散華女子学園の２年生
My mom is the hostess here,
the Saoji Kaiseki Kitchen,
母は　ここ
京懐石「さおうじ」の女将
and my dad is the head cook.
父は料理長　つまり私は
生まれついてのお店の娘
In other words,
I was a born restaurateur's daughter.
Ever since I was little,
I frequently helped out,
小さい頃から　ちょくちょく
手伝いをしていたし
- and at times when they
were shorthanded, like now,
時々　手が足りないと　こうして
便利に駆り出されてしまう
- Delicious again today, as always.
- and at times when they
were shorthanded, like now,
- Compliments to the chef.
- I serve as a handy fill-in.
Thank you very much!
ありがとうございました
Eggplant
Hey, come on!
ほらほら　もっとサクサク
手を動かして
You've gotta get your
hands moving faster than that.
Shut up! Don't startle me
like that! I could cut off a finger!
（千紘）うっせえよ
いきなり声かけんな　指切るだろ
And why should I even have to
lend a hand here in your kitchen?
何で俺が　お前んちの店
手伝わなきゃなんないんだ
せっかくの日曜だっつうのに
そんな冷たいこと言うなよ
I only get one Sunday a week.
Oh, don't be such a wet blanket!
いッ！
長いつきあいでしょ
We've known each other too long, right?
Come on, your hands are standing still.
ほら　手が止まってる
お前が止めてんだろ！
You're the one who stopped me, right?!
Only because you're dawdling around.
そっちが
のたくたやってるからじゃない
Oh, my...
Watching you like this, you're like
a perfect young married couple.
こうやって見てると
似合いの若夫婦みたいね
Mom!
お母さん！
ウフフッ　大丈夫よ千紘くん
It's okay, Chihiro. Once you two get married,
I wouldn't ask you to take over the business.
結婚しても
うちを継げなんて言わないから
You can pay us no mind,
until the chance comes along,
気にせずチャンスがあったら
どんどん押し倒していいのよ
and then swoop right in
and take over. Right, dear?
ねッ　あなた
What are you talking about?
何言ってんのよ　もう　あッ！
Hey!
おい！
Be careful.
気をつけろよ
ゴメンゴメン
Sorry, sorry.
Oh, hot stuff, you two!
おッ　熱いね　ご両人！
You don't have to be in
such a hurry to let go, you know.
別に慌てて離さなくてもいいのに
Hmm? What?
何？
何でもない！
Nothing!
When I first met Chihiro, I was in kindergarten.
千紘と初めて会ったのは
私が幼稚園の頃だった
In romantic dramas and such,
よく　恋愛ドラマとかで最悪の
出会いをして大嫌いだった人を
there are couples who meet in the worst way,
and hate each other,
until they find out more about each other,
色々知っていってだんだん好きに
なっていくっていうのがあるけど
and slowly fall in love...
But me and Chihiro's first meeting...
私と千紘の出会いは最高だった
...was the best.
You're not scared?
怖くないの？
I'm not scared one bit.
全然怖くないよ
I thought a prince had appeared before me.
私は王子様が現れたと思った
Uncle Do'on told me who
this prince was the next day.
その王子様の正体は次の日
呶恩おじさんが教えてくれた
蘭子ちゃん　この子は
うちの息子の千紘だ
Ranko, this is my son, Chihiro.
He's a year younger than you,
but I hope you two will get along.
１つ年下だけど
仲良くしてやってくれな
Mm-hmm.
うん　千紘くん
Chihiro...
Let's go play!
遊ぼう
うん
I was absolutely determined to be friends with him.
私は彼と絶対
仲良くなろうと思った
わ～ッ
映画見るの？
We're watching a movie?
Uh-huh. It's a great one.
うん　面白いよ
へえ～ッ
Chihiro...
千紘くん
Chihiro!
千紘くん！
What?
なあに？
Let's go outside!
お外　行こう
How come?
何で？
Let's go play outside.
お外で遊ぼうよ
Too much trouble.
めんどくさい
お外　行こう
Let's go outside!
Chihiro, what do you usually do for fun?
千紘くんは
いつも何して遊ぶの？
Watch zombie movies.
ゾンビ映画を見る
What about besides zombie movies?
ゾンビ映画の他は？
ゾンビの本を読む
Read zombie magazines.
What about besides zombies?
ゾンビの他は？
ご飯を食べる
I eat food.
That's not something you do for fun.
それは遊ぶのと違うでしょ
Wow! How pretty!
うわ～ッ　キレイ
Chihiro! Let's use these and play house...
千紘くん　これで
おままごとしよう…
Whatcha doing?
何してんの？
I heard they bury bodies under cherry trees.
桜の木の下には
死体が埋まってるんだって
えッ？
ゾンビが埋まってるかもしれない
Maybe there are zombies buried under here.
Huh? Stop it. I'm scared by that.
えッ　やめようよ
そんなこと怖いよ
Huh? If it isn't Chihiro, from the temple.
あれッ　寺の千紘じゃん
You're right.
ホントだ
うわッ　女と遊んでるんだ
Whoa, he's playing with a girl!
Ew, yuck!
かっちょわりい～
俺達に遊んでもらえないから
He couldn't get us to play with him,
so he had to get a
girl to play with him, instead?
女に遊んでもらってんのかよ
気持ちわりい
How gross!
What is your problem?! What's wrong
with him playing with a girl?!
何よ　あんた達！　女の子と
遊ぶののどこが悪いの！
ううッ…
あッ　千紘くん？
Huh? Chihiro?
うッ　うわ～ん！
Chihiro!
千紘くん！
Ha-ha! He's crying again!
ヘヘッ　また泣いた～
He really does cry over anything, huh?
あいつ　ホントすぐ泣くよな
泣けばいいと思ってんじゃない
Maybe he thinks it's okay to cry.
私が見込んだ王子様は　実は
ただのゾンビ好きの変人で
The boy I took to be a prince
was actually a zombie-loving weirdo,
めんどくさがり屋で協調性のない
ヘタレの泣き虫だったのでした
who was inactive and unsociable,
and a good-for-nothing crybaby.
He was only comfortable in the cemetery
墓地が平気だったのはゾンビ映画で
お墓を見慣れていたのと
because he was used to
seeing graves in zombie movies,
and because they were
a part of the family homestead.
実家だったからというだけで…
As a result, when it was time to leave,
というわけで
帰る頃にはすっかり
- any hots I'd had for him had grown cold.
私の恋心も冷めてしまっていた
- I'm sorry I couldn't offer you anything more.
- any hots I'd had for him had grown cold.
Oh, no, I'm just sorry
that whenever we come here,
いや～　ここに来ると　いっつも
羽を伸ばしちゃって　すみません
we let loose so much.
If you'd like,
please come visit again at festival time,
よかったら盆暮れと言わず
遊びに来てください
or any other time.
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございます
あれッ　柚菜さんは？
Huh? Where is Izuna?
Well, Mero has come down with a fever,
so they went to the hospital.
それが萌路が熱を出してしまって
病院へ行ってるんですよ
Th-They did? I wish
we could have seen them off.
そうなの？　だったら
見送りなんてよかったのに
Oh, no, it's not a big deal.
いやいや
大したことじゃないんだ
Well, Brother, see you later.
じゃあ兄さん　また
Ranko, don't you want to say goodbye to Chihiro?
蘭子　千紘くんに
さよなら言わなくていいの？
No.
Sheesh, how is it, when I was
called in to help in the kitchen,
たく　厨房の手伝いで呼ばれた俺が
that I have to do deliveries, too?
何で配達まで
しなきゃなんないんだよ
Because you're not a lot of
help in the kitchen, of course.
その厨房で
大して役に立たないからじゃん
I can't help it. I've barely
even held a kitchen knife before.
しょうがねえだろ　包丁なんて
ほとんど持ったことねえから
Well, I suppose.
まあ　そうだよね
So, why are you tagging along, Wanko?
何で　わんこがついてきてんだよ
千紘だけだと　お客様に
ろくな挨拶もしないでしょ
Chihiro, you can't pay a
proper greeting to the customer alone.
That's going to have an effect
on their confidence in our restaurant.
それじゃ　うちの店の信用に
かかわるからね
Hey, I'm not that daft!
そこまで非常識じゃねえ
できるっつの挨拶くらい
I can handle a simple greeting.
Hey, Chihiro!
こら　千紘！　ブツブツ
言わんでしっかり働け！
Less complaining, more hard work!
いッ…
蘭子ちゃん　今日もありがとう
Ranko, thanks for coming today.
Oh, no, don't be silly.
いえいえ　とんでもありません
千紘のヤツは
好きなだけ　こき使っていいよ
Feel free to work Chihiro
just as hard as you'd like to.
いつもお世話になってるからね
You're always looking after us, after all.
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
Uh, don't I get any veto power here?
え～ッ　俺に
拒否権はないんでしょうか？
- No.
ない
Aw, man...
あと何軒だ？
２軒
How many more stops?
Two more.
何　そんなに手伝うのイヤだった？
What, you dislike helping me that much?
No, it's not that. I'm concerned about Rea.
そういうわけじゃねえけど
ほら　礼弥のことも気になるし
ああ　礼弥さんね
Ah yes, Miss Rea...
Hey! I told you, it's not like that!
おい　だから　そういうんじゃ
ないって言ってるだろ
There's still all sorts of things I don't know,
まだ分かんないことだらけだし
安定してねえっつうか
and things haven't really stabilized...
Okay, I get it.
分かってるって
You do?
そっか
She's weighing on your mind.
Miss Rea is cute, and all.
気になるよね
礼弥さんカワイイもんね～
Y-You don't get it at all, do you?!
全然分かってねえじゃねえか！
あ～ッ　それって
デートか　デートなのか？
Is this, by any chance,
a date?! Is this a date?!
Huh? I-Is this a date?
えッ　デートなんですか？
Are you dense? Of course it's not.
アホか　そんなわけねえだろ
Hey, you! You don't have
to deny it so directly, you know.
ちょっと　真っ向から
否定しなくてもいいでしょ
But it's not a date, right?
だって　デートじゃねえじゃん
何？
What? Is it really that
loathsome for you to call it that?
そういう風に言われるの
そんなにイヤ？
I never said it was loathsome!
イヤとかそんなんじゃねえよ
う～ん
Hold on!
待て待て　それはひょっとして
This wouldn't be...
...the sort of lovers' spat
that I've heard about, would it?!
恋人同士がやるという
憧れの痴話ゲンカってやつじゃ？
Huh?
えッ？
違えよ
No, it's not!
あ～れ～
Damn! First Rea, now Ranko!
くっそ～
礼弥さんといい　蘭子さんといい
Why are all the girls attracted only to you?!
なぜに　お前ばかりがモテるのだ！
You, the guy who absurdly enough,
しかも　お前はゾンビにしか
興味がないとか　たわごと抜かすし
is interested in nothing but zombies!
Is it composure? Is it your composure?!
余裕か？　余裕なのか？
俺をバカにしてんのか？
Are you doing this to mock me?!
That's what it is, damn you!
してんだろ　こんちきしょ～！
ヤスタカくん　落ち着いて
Yasutaka, calm down.
How can I keep calm about this?
これが落ち着いていられるか！
I can't take any more of you.
つきあいきれんな
Miss Ranko, what is it you see in this guy?
蘭子さん　どうして
こんなヤツがいいんですか？
He's a zombie freak with a warped
personality, who's not handsome,
こいつなんで大したイケメンでもない
ゾンビおたくのひねくれ者の
and also a slacker, who's a stubborn,
good-for-nothing chicken!
めんどくさがりで
がんこなへタレ野郎です
Yeah, he is that.
そうなんだけどね
You're not going to deny it?
否定しねえのかよ　ってか
And aren't you the sick bastard
who's obsessed with pretty girls?
お前だって美少女おたくの
変態野郎じゃ
そのとおり
そこに俺は誇りを持っているぞ
You are correct! In fact,
I hold it as a badge of pride!
And if you weren't so popular with girls,
I wouldn't have a problem!
お前もモテないなら文句ねえ
I'm not popular with girls, though!
だから　モテてねえって
You still deny it, you glory-hog?!
まだ言うか　この増上慢が
２人とも落ち着いてよ
俺は落ち着いてるよ
Calm down, both of you!
I am calm.
The next time I saw Chihiro
was two years after the first time.
私が千紘と再会したのは
初めて会ってから
２年後のことだった
When I was six, my dad had a strong desire
私が６歳の頃
父の強い意向で
to move the restaurant the
family ran from Chiba to here, in Shiyo.
千葉でやっていた　うちのお店を
ここ　紫陽町に移した
うちは千紘の寺と
ご近所になった
Our home ended up being
very close to Chihiro's temple.
And then, shortly thereafter,
そして　しばらくして母の誘いで
千紘がうちに遊びにきたのだ
Chihiro came over to visit,
at my mom's invitation.
２年前　恋が冷めたとはいえ
いとこなんだから
And though my love
for him had waned two years earlier,
he was still my cousin,
and I decided that we would be playmates.
ちゃんと遊び相手になろうと
私は思っていた
千紘くん
Chihiro...
遊ぼう　ゲームとかする？
Let's play. Want to play a game or something?
No.
しない
じゃあ　お外に行こうか
Then, how about we go outside?
No.
行かない
Nothing's changed at all.
全然変わってない
Here, I brought some snacks.
は～い　おやつ持ってきましたよ
Chihiro, now that we live
in the same neighborhood,
千紘くん
せっかく近所になったんだから
蘭子と仲良くやってね
you play nice with Ranko, okay?
Oh, you're so bashful!
もう　テレ屋なんだから
カワイイわね～
- How adorable!
昔から　なぜか母は
千紘を気に入っていて
- For some reason,
- How adorable!
- my mom always liked Chihiro,
- Stop it! Stop it!
私と仲良くさせようとしていた
それも私の気分を下げていた
and tried to get him and
me to get along with each other.
That also got me down.
You really are so adorable!
ホント　カワイイんだから
ねッ　蘭子
Right, Ranko?
Oh, Ranko!
あら　蘭子
Where's Chihiro?
千紘くんは？
Upstairs, reading a magazine.
上で本　読んでる
Why don't you play with him?
何で一緒に遊ばないの？
Chihiro says he won't play with me.
千紘くんが
遊ばないって言うんだもん
He says he doesn't want
to play games, or go outside.
ゲームも　お外もイヤだって
じゃあ　近くのレンタルビデオ屋さんに
行ってらっしゃい
Well, why don't you go to
that video rental place nearby?
Remember, you said that there
was an anime you wanted to watch?
ほら
このあいだ
見たいアニメあるって
You can go rent that,
and watch it together, can't you?
あれ借りてきて　一緒に見れば？
Oh? Ranko, are you the kind of
girl who leaves her cousin all alone
あれッ？
蘭子は来てくれた　いとこを
ほったらかしにする子なの？
when he comes over to visit?
All right.
分かった
It's this way.
こっちだよ
I know.
知ってる
"DVD Video"
Chihiro?
千紘くん　うわ～ッ！
Hey, Chihiro!
ねえねえ　千紘くん
What?
何？
アニメにしない？
面白いのがあるからさ
Let's get an anime. I know a real good one.
This one is more fun.
これのが面白いよ
"Zombie Academy: School Festival of Horror"
"Zombie Academy: Culture Festival of Horror."
ゾンビ学園　惨劇の文化祭
Oh, that's my Chihiro.
You know, I have the latest picture,
おッ　さすが千紘くん
それだったら最新作　アメリカから
買ってきたのが奥にあるけど
which I bought from America,
in the back. Want to see it?
見るかい？
Yes!
見ます！
My goodness, Chihiro is
amazing. Only five years old,
まったく　千紘くんはすごいよ
５歳なのにホラー映画だけは
吹き替えなしで見られる
and he only watches horror movies,
and they're not even dubbed.
There. Ah, and it's a bit extreme,
so don't tell your mom and dad.
はい
ああ　ちょっと過激だから
お父さん　お母さんに内緒な
Uh-huh.
Say, what's "extreme"?
ねえ　過激って？
It means the zombies' gunky stuff is incredible.
ゾンビのでろでろが
すごいってこと
What gunky stuff?
でろでろって…
I wonder what the gunky stuff will be like.
どんな感じなんだろう？
でろでろ…
How come you decided
what to watch without asking me?
何で勝手に
見るもの決めちゃったの？
It's okay. I promise you, this will be good.
大丈夫
これ絶対　面白いから
このシリーズは鉄板だから
This whole series is first-rate.
I don't like horror, though.
ホラーとか好きじゃないもの
But if you watch it, I'm sure you'll like it.
でも　見たら
きっと好きになるよ
But it's in English, right?
でも英語でしょ？
It's still fun to watch, even if
you don't understand the words.
言葉分からなくても面白いから
It's not fun for me! I wanted to watch anime!
私は面白くないの！
私はアニメが見たかったの！
Mm-mm, this is far more fun than anime.
ううん　絶対アニメより面白いよ
私はホラーよりアニメがいいの
I like anime better than horror!
こんなの返してくる！
I'm taking this back!
えッ　蘭子ちゃん！
Huh? Ranko!
蘭子ちゃん…
Ranko!
うわ～ッ　あっちいけ！
Get away!
千紘くん…
Chihiro...
うわ～ん！
Chihiro, thank you for helping me.
千紘くん
助けてくれてありがとう
Mm-hmm.
Looking back on it now,
maybe it really was love at first sight
今　振り返ると
やっぱり墓地で会ったときから
when I first met him in the cemetery.
一目ぼれだったのかもしれない
And so, by the time I was ten,
そして私は　１０歳の頃には
もう間違いなく
千紘のことが好きだった
I had fallen in love with Chihiro, without a doubt.
Listen, Chihiro...
あのさ　千紘
Huh?
Chihiro, what would you
like your first kiss to be like?
千紘はさ　初めてのキスって
どんな感じがいい？
うん？　どんなって？
Huh? Be like?
Y-You know, there's lots of ways, right?
ほら　色々あるじゃない
Against the backdrop of the sea at sunset,
夕焼けの海をバックにとか
旅立つ恋人との別れ際とか
or when a lover is leaving on a trip,
for example...
Let's see...
え～っと…
I guess I'd like to smooch
with a zombie girl, like that.
やっぱ　こういうゾンビっ娘と
チュッチュしたいな
A-Again with the zombie girls?
またゾンビっ娘？
Do you really think there
are girls out there like that?
そんな子が
ホントにいると思ってんの？
いるかもじゃ～ん
Maybe there are.
もっとちゃんと考えなさいよ
Think about it harder!
A kiss is something important!
キスって大事なことなんだよ！
Yeah, yeah...
Geez...!
もう！
降谷！　そのうちお前には
天罰が落ちるからな！
Furuya!
You'll get your comeuppance soon enough!
Or you could introduce me to a girl!
もしくは　俺に女の子を紹介しろ！
Man, what a pest. Okay,
let's go on to the last two stops.
たく　しつこいヤツだな
さあ　あと２軒行こうぜ
Chihiro...
千紘
うん？
Here, take my hand.
手　つないで
えッ　何で？
Huh? Why?
いいから　つなげ！
Just do it, okay?!
Ow-w-w-w! Okay, okay!
痛い痛い痛い
分かった　分かったって！
フフーン
じゃあ行こっか
何なんだよ
Okay, let's go.
What is your deal?
千紘
何？
Chihiro...
What?
私達が初めて手をつないだのって
いつか覚えてる？
Do you remember the first time we held hands?
Uh, that would be...
when we first met, wouldn't it?
う～ん　それって
初めて会ったときじゃねえか？
You were crying in the cemetery,
お前が墓地で泣いてて
仕方ねえから俺が手を引いてさ
and I had no choice
but to take you by the hand.
Huh? Was that it?
What's the right answer?
あれッ　違ったっけ？
正解は何だよ
覚えてないよ　そんな昔のこと
I don't remember anything that far back.
はあッ？　何だよそれ
Huh? What's your problem?
I don't get you.
意味分かんねえ
Deliveries are complete!
配達終了
こんなお屋敷にも届けてるんだ
You even deliver to big houses like this, huh?
Mm-hmm.
The old lady who lives
here has been a big fan of ours
ここのおばあちゃんが　おととしの
法事でうちのお弁当を食べて以来
ever since she had one
of our bento lunches two years ago,
ファンになってくれてさ
時々　注文してくれるんだ
at a memorial service.
She orders from us once in a while.
ふ～ん
Chihiro, your work duties are now over.
千紘は　ここで業務終了
帰っていいよ
You can go home.
えッ？
大体ピークは越えたし
We're past our peak hours already,
so there's no point in
having you come back to help.
戻って手伝ってもらわなくても
内輪で　まわせそうだから
We can handle the
rest of the day on our own.
You mean it? Lucky me!
マジか？　ラッキー！
じゃあな
Okay, see you!
What's wrong?
何だよ　わッ！
What's... going on...?
どうしたん…
空気にのまれてキスされそうに
なってんじゃないわよ
Don't act so intimidated
when you're about to be kissed.
はあッ？
もっと　ちゃんと考えなさいよ！
Think about things a little harder!
A kiss is something very important!
キスって大事なことなんだよ！
やっぱり　負けたくない
I really... don't want to be beaten out...
I swear...
絶対に　絶対に
...I won't be beaten out!!
負けないんだから～ッ！
ハア　ハア　ハア
Hitotsu dake kanau no nara
If I had just one wish
kimi no te no naka yureru chiisa na hana de itai
I would want to be a small flower, trembling in your hands
Hajimete miru mabushii kono sekai ga
Even if I become separated from you,
kimi to moshi hagureta to shite mo kitto
in this bright world I'm seeing for the first time,
mitsukedashite
I'm sure I'll find you
Mezametara soba ni iru yo
When I wake up, I'll stay beside you
ashita mo
tomorrow as well
Preview
ホントにいいんですか？　私で
Are you sure about having me do this?
萌路ちゃんに
話は通してあるんですよね？
You have spoken to Mero about this, right?
なら　いいんですけど…
Well then, all right.
"Counterfeit... Freedom..."
Next time on Sankarea, episode 8:
- Huh?
- Mero!
萌路ちゃん…
プロデューサー プロデューサー\はどこかな？
The producer... Where is the producer...?
萌路ちゃん　これはね…
Mero, you see...
プロデューサー どういうことか
説明してもらおうか
Mr. Producer, would you
mind explaining this to me?!